<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Scrolling Text</string>
    <string name="article_title">Anxiety</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">Types of anxiety</string>
    <string name="article_text">The notes here on the different kinds of anxiety and are not meant to give a diagnosis. But you might find them useful if, when you see a doctor, psychologist or counsellor they use these terms.\n\n
        There are different kinds of anxiety disorders, but these are the most common:\n\n
        <b>Generalised Anxiety Disorder</b> <i>()GAD)</i> is when people worry about a number of things, on most days for six or more months. It usually affects young adults, and women more than men. The anxiety is about a wide range of situations and issues, not just one specific event. It can be hard to control it and finds its way into all parts of daily life.\n\n
        <b>Phobias</b> are extreme and irrational fears about a particular thing. The can be so great that the person goes to great lengths to avoid it, even if it’s harmless. For example social phobia is fear of being judged or embarrassed in public, even in everyday situations like when eating, speaking at work or making small talk.  Another type is agoraphobia, often thought to be a fear of open spaces. It is also a fear of being closed in, or away from a safe place or person who makes you feel safe. It can be extremely disabling and frightening, and can leave people unable to leave their home.\n\n
        <b>Obsessive Compulsive Disorder</b> <i>(OCD)</i> is when a person has unwanted, intrusive, persistent or repetitive thoughts (whakaaro), feelings, ideas, or sensations (obsessions) which cause anxiety. So they then carry out actions to reduce the anxiety or get rid of those thoughts. For example, the person may be afraid of germs and try to relieve the anxiety through repeated hand washing or avoiding touching things like door knobs. They may know these thoughts (whakaaro) are unreasonable but be unable to stop them. When OCD is severe and left untreated, it can be very distressing, and get in the way of work (mahi), school (kura) and normal life at home.\n\n
        <b>Post-traumatic Stress Disorder</b> <i>(PTSD)</i> is a reaction to a highly stressful event outside the range of everyday experience when a person feels very unsafe or threatened. These are unsual experiences such as war, violent attack (verbal, physical or sexual) or a natural disaster. The symptoms usually include irritability, anxiety, flashbacks, repeated nightmares, and avoiding situations that might bring back memories of the event.
        <b>Panic Disorder</b> is when a person has panic attacks. These are intense feelings of anxiety along with the kind of physical symptoms and overwhelming sensations you would have if you were in great danger, like a pounding heart, feeling faint, sweating, shaky limbs, nausea, chest pains, breathing discomfort and feelings of losing control. The symptoms rise and peak rapidly. The effects can be so severe that people experiencing panic attacks can believe they are dying. Despite being frightening and very uncomfortable they are not life threatening.\n\n
        For more information check the website https://depression.org.nz/is-it-depression-anxiety/anxiety/</string>
</resources>
